Finding Aid for the Sterling Silliphant Papers, 1957-1985
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Teleplays.
  - The Chrysler Theater
    - (Box 16)
      - "Murder In the First", 1964 July 17; 1 teleplay (carbon). (Box 16)
      - "Murder In the First", 1964 July 20; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "Murder In the First", 1964 July 27; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "The Shattered Glass.", 1964 September 1; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "The Highest Fall of All.", 1965 August 20; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "The Highest Fall of All.", 1 duplicate copy, incomplete. (Box 16)
      - "The Cloudbusters.", 1965 October 25; 1 story outline with holograph corrections. (Box 16)
      - "The Cloudbusters.", 1965 December 3; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "The Cloudbusters.", 1965 December 23; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "The Cloudbusters.", 1966 March 2; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
      - "The Cloudbusters.", 1966 March 28; 1 teleplay. (Box 16)
  - The Day The World Ended, Addition, 11/82.
    - Production file. v.p., 1977-1979; ca. 150 leaves. (Box 92, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence, memos, cast list, staff and crew list, continuity chart, housing list.
    - Step outline. n.p., 1977 April; by Stirling Silliphant; 35 pages. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Step outline. n.p., 1977 April; by Stirling Silliphant; 37 pages. Typescript. (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - Another copy., Transcript (carbon) (Box 92, Folder 11)
      - Another copy., Typescript (photocopy) (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - [Screenplay breakdown] n.p., 1977 May; ca. 160 pages. Typescript, typescript (multilith) with holograph corrections. (Box 92, Folder 13)
      A breakdown of the previous screenplay with indications of where new scenes will be played and a brief summary of their intent and content by Stirling Silliphant.
    - [Screenplay breakdown] n.p., 1977 May; ca. 160 pages. Typescript (photocopy) (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - [Screenplay breakdown] n.p., 1977 May; 27 pages. Typescript (carbon) (Box 93, Folder 2)
      Does not include text of the screenplay.
    - Characters. n.p., 1977 May; by Stirling Silliphant; 43 pages. Typescript, typescript (photocopy) with holograph corrections. (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Characters. n.p., 1977 May; by Stirling Silliphant; 12 pages. Typescript (carbon). (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Another copy., Typescript (multilith) (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - The Day The World Ended. n.p., 1978 June; Written by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; 135 pages. Typescript (multilith). Fourth revised first draft. (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - The Day The World Ended. n.p., 1978 December; Written by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; 150 pages. Typescript (multilith) with holograph corrections by Stirling Silliphant. First revised first draft. (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - The Day The World Ended. n.p., 1978 December; Written by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; 150 pages. Typescript (carbon). Fifth revised first draft. (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - The Day The World Ended. n.p., 1979 January; Written by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; ca. 100 pages. Typescript (photocopy), typescript with holograph corrections by Stirling Silliphant. Sixth revised first draft. Incomplete. (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - The Day The World Ended. n.p., 1979 January; Written by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; ca. 100 pages. Typescript (multilith), typescript with holograph corrections by Stirling Silliphant. Sixth revised first draft. (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - The Day The World Ended. n.p., 1979 January; Written by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; ca. 200 pages. Typescript (multilith), typescript with holograph corrections by Stirling Silliphant. Sixth revised first draft. With cover. (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Screenplay. n.p., 1979 February; by Carl Foreman and Stirling Silliphant.; ca. 200 pages. Typescript (multilith). Shooting final. With cover. (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Partial screenplay. n.p., undated.; ca. 100 pages. Typescript (multilith) with holograph corrections. (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Revised pages. n.p., 1978 June 1; ca. 50 pages. Typescript (multilith) with holograph corrections. (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - With this: Revised pages. n.p., 1978 June 1; ca. 50 pages. Typescript (photocopy) (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous pages. n.p., undated; 17 pages. Typescript (carbon). (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - The First Thirty-Six Hours of Dr. Durant, The teleplay entitled The First Thirty-Six Hours of Dr. Durant was originally entitled A Small Step Forward. Versions of the teleplay are arranged in chronological order of revision, each teleplay or section incororating changes of the previous versions.
    - A small step forward., Written by Stirling Silliphant.; [14 folders.] (Box 75, Folder 9-13, Box 76, Folder 1-10)
      - Teleplay., 1973 December 18; Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Teleplay., 1973 December 18; Typescript (carbon) (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Teleplay., 1973 December 18; Typescript photocopy. (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Teleplay., 1973 December 18; Created and developed by Stirling Silliphant and Art Frankel.; Typescript photocopy with holograph notes by Robin Cook. (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Teleplay., 1974 February 8; Typescript and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - Teleplay., Revised 1974 February 8; Typescript (carbon). (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - Teleplay., Revised 1974 February 8; Typescript. (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - Teleplay., 1974 February 11; Typescript multilith. Two copies. (Box 76, Folder 3-4)
      - Teleplay., 1975 February 26; Typescript multilith. Two copies. (Box 76, Folder 5-6)
        "Final draft February 26, 1975."
      - Teleplay., 1975 March 10; Typescript multilith. Four copies. (Box 76, Folder 7-10)
        "Revised final draft March 10, 1975."
    - Revised pages of teleplay organized by date and stage of revision, 1975 February 10-1975 March 19.; In 6 folders. (Box 76, Folder 11, Box 77, Folder 1-5)
      - Revised pages., 1975 February 10; Typescript and typescript multilith with holograph corrections. (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - Revised pages., 1975 February 12.; Typescript (carbon). (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Revised pages., 1975 February 28.; Typescript multilith. (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Revised pages., 1975 March 13.; Typescript multilith. (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Revised pages., 1975 March 17.; Typescript multilith with holograph corrections. (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Revised pages., 1975 March 19.; Typescript multilith. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and production notes., 80 items. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Research material., 10 items. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Notes for teleplay by Stirling Silliphant., 3 items. (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - The Looking Glass, Addition, 11/82.
    - Episode Two. n.p., 1982 February; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; 103 pages. Typescript (photocopy) with holograph corrections. Final draft. (Box 103, Folder 9)
      Episode two (two hours) of a three episode limited series (six hours).
    - Episode Three. n.p., 1982 February; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; 122 pages. Typescript (photocopy) with holograph corrections. Final draft. (Box 103, Folder 10)
      Episode three (two hours) of a three episode limited series (six hours).
    - Episode Three. n.p., 1982 February; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; 123 pages. Typescript (carbon) with holograph corrections. Final draft. (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - The Medex
    - (Box 39)
      Casting information and photographs; Correspondence, newsclippings, story synopses, title credits.
    - 1971 September 20., Two copies of typescript with holograph corrections [teleplay] (Box 45)
    - 1971 October 20., Second draft typescript [teleplay] (Box 45)
    - Revised draft of typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 45)
    - 1971 October 18., Revised draft, carbon. (Box 45)
    - 1971 October 13., Typescript storyline. (Box 45)
    - 1971 September 21., Typescript of first draft. (Box 45)
    - 1971 September 20., Carbon. (Box 45)
    - 1971 September 17., First draft typescript with holograph corrections [teleplay] (Box 45)
    - 1971 September 14., First draft typescript carbon [teleplay] (Box 45)
    - 1971 September 14., First draft typescript [teleplay] (Box 45)
    - 1971 September 20., Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 45)
    - 1971 November 5., Typescript with holograph corrections [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - 1972 January 5, Final shooting script of typescript [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - Second draft. (Box 46)
    - 1972 January 5, Final shooting script carbon [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - 1971 November 5., Carbon, section [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - 1972 January, Four copies of typescript, staff and crew list (Box 46)
    - 1971 December 8., Third draft of typescript with holograph corrections [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - 1971 December 8., Third draft carbon [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - 1971 December 8., Third draft typescript [teleplay] (Box 46)
    - 1972 January 5, Final shooting script, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 46)
    - 1972 January 7, Two copies of typescript schedule. (Box 47)
    - 1972 January 6, Four copies of final shooting script, typescript [teleplay] (Box 47)
    - 1972 January 10, Typescript list of principals. (Box 47)
    - 1972 January 7, Five copies of revised final shooting script, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 47)
    - 1972 January 7, Five copies of revised final shooting script, typescript carbon. (Box 47)
    - 1972 January 7, Five copies of revised final shooting script, typescript carbon. (Box 47)
  - Tightrope!, n.p.
    - 1959 June 20, 1 teleplay. (Box 1)
- Motion Picture Screenplays
  - A Walk In the Spring Rain, Pingree Productions, Inc.
    - 1969 February 5., 1 screenplay (carbon) (Box 24)
    - 1969 March 5., 1 "second revised draft" of the screenplay. (Box 24)
    - 1969 February 5., 1 screenplay (photocopy). (Box 24)
    - 1969, Scripts. (Box 29-30)
    - 3 folders. (Box 35)
    - (Box 35)
      Advertising and promotion; Ingrid Bergman; Budget; Call sheets; Cast; Casting; Contracts.
    - Correspondence., 1 folder. (Box 36)
    - Costumes (Box 36)
    - Crew (Box 36)
    - Daily production reports (Box 36)
    - Expenses (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
    - Locations (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 36)
    - Publicity and advertising (Box 36)
    - Publicity tour (Box 36)
    - Publicity., 1 folder. (Box 36)
    - Publicity., 1 folder. (Box 37)
    - Sets (Box 37)
    - Anthony Quinn (Box 37)
    - Script changes. (Box 37)
  - Between Hello and Goodbye, Pingree Productions, Inc.
    - 1966 July 17., 1 film treatment with holograph corrections. (Box 20)
  - Big Boo Bam
    - undated., First draft, typescript [screenplay]. (Box 41)
    - 1971 August 13., Two copies of typescript [screenplay] (Box 41)
  - Breakout
    - Screenplay. n.p., 1974 February 21; by Cal Biggs.; Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Screenplay., 1974 February 21; by Cal Biggs.; Typescript. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Screenplay., 1974 February 21; by Cal Biggs.; Typescript (carbon). (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Screenplay. First draft., 1974 March 15.; by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript photocopy. (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Screenplay. Revised first draft., 1974 April 18; by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections.. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Revised pages of screenplay organized by date and stage of revision., 1974 February 22-1974 April 28; In 3 folders. (Box 78, Folder 2-4)
      - Revised pages., 1974 February 22; Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Revised pages., 1974 March 22; Typescript and typescript (carbon) with holograph corrections. (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Revised pages. "Revised first draft," [revised pages only], 1974 April 28; Typescript (carbon). (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Revised pages., undated.; Typescript (carbon). (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Step-line., undated.; Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. v.p., 1974-1975.; 7 items. Typescript (carbon), typescript (photocopy). (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Charly, n.p.
    - Various pages of the screenplay, with holograph corrections. (Box 20-21)
    - 1967 July 3., 2 copies of the screenplay, both carbon, one with holograph corrections. (Box 20-21)
    - 1966 October 21., 1 revised step-outline. (Box 20-21)
    - 1967 March 15., 2 copies of the screenplay, one with holograph corrections. (Box 20-21)
    - 1966 October 18., 1 step-outline of scenes (Box 20-21)
    - Correspondence. v.p., ca. 1973-1976. (Box 20-21)
    - 1967 January 30., 5 copies of the screenplay, 2 of which are typescript with holograph corrections, 1 carbon and 2 mimeographed copies. (Box 20-21)
    - 1966 October 24., 10 revised step-outlines, 1 of which is typescript with holograph corrections, and the other 9 are mimeographed copies. (Box 20-21)
    - Correspondence, etc. relating to motion pictures, 1966 August 23.; 1 reel (7 in.) 3 3/4 ips. Tape. (Box 25)
      Discussion between Ralph Nelson and Cliff Robertson of problems encoundered during the production of "Charly." Los Angeles.
    - Correspondence, etc. relating to motion pictures, 1 folder. (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, etc. relating to motion pictures, 1 folder. (Box 25)
      Publicity material.
    - Screenplay., 1967. (Box 32)
    - Correspondence., 1972. (Box 38)
  - Cloudbusters
    - Script., 1966 April 18 (Box 32)
  - Death Scream, Earlier versions of Death Scream were entitled Society of Pygmies and Rodriguez.
    - Society of pygmies., 1974 December 24; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Society of pygmies., 1975 January 9; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript photocopy. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Rodriguez., 1975 March 26; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Final draft. Typescript multilith. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Rodriguez., 1975 April 22; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Final draft. Typescript multilith. Signed. (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Revised pages organized by date and stage of revision., 1974 March 20-1975 May 5; In 3 folders. (Box 79, Folder 5-7)
      - Revised pages., 1974 March 20; Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Revised pages., 1975 May 1; Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Revised pages., 1975 May 5; Typescript multilith. Signed. (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Revised pages., undated.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Fly Away Home, Addition, 11/82.
    - Pages from a screenplay. n.p., 1980-1981; ca. 50 pages. Typescript. (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - For Better, For Worse
    - Screenplay., 1962. (Box 32)
  - In the Heat of the Night, The Mirisch Corporation.
    - 1966 January 7., 1 step-outline (carbon). (Box 19-20)
    - 1966 January 7., 1 step-outline with holograph corrections. (Box 19-20)
    - 1965 December 15., 1 character notes and step-outline. (Box 19-20)
    - 1966 January - February, 1 first-draft screenplay (carbon). (Box 19-20)
    - 1966 July 1., 1 screenplay. (Box 19-20)
    - 1966 July 5., 1 screenplay with holograph corrections. (Box 19-20)
    - Correspondence, etc. relating to motion pictures, 1 folder. (Box 26)
      Clippings, articles, dealing with awards won.
    - Correspondence, etc. relating to motion pictures, 1 folder. (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, etc. relating to motion pictures, 1 folder. (Box 26)
    - Letters and telegrams of congratulations., 2 folders. (Box 26)
  - Killer Elite
    - Screenplay., undated [released 1975]; by Stirling Silliphant from the novel by Robert Rostand.; Typescript and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Screenplay., undated [released 1975]; by Stirling Silliphant from the novel by Robert Rostand.; Typescript multilith and typescript with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Revised pages of script organized by date and stage of revision., undated.; Typescript with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence. v.p., 1975-1977; 15 items. Typescript, typescript (carbon) (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Maracaibo
    - 1954-1955., Scrapbook of clippings. (Box 34)
  - Marlowe
    - Publicity., 2 items. (Box 37)
  - Mayday!
    - 1967 August 30., Typescript with holograph corrections, first draft screenplay. (Box 42)
    - 1967 August 30., Typescript carbon, first draft screenplay. (Box 42)
    - 1967 August 18, 21, 24, 25; 1967 November 7, Five typescripts [screenplay] with holograph corrections. (Box 42)
    - 1967 November 11, Typescript, revised first draft of screenplay. (Box 42)
    - 1967 August 30, Typescript, first draft screenplay. (Box 42)
  - Meteor, Addition, 11/82.
    - Screenplay. n.p., 1976 November 22; by Steven Bach.; 143 pages. Typescript. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Screenplay. n.p., 1976 November 22; by Steven Bach.; 143 pages. Typescript (carbon). (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Screenplay. n.p., 1976 November 22; by Steven Bach.; ca. 140 pages. Typescript (photocopy) with holograph corrections.. (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Midway, Earlier versions of this screenplay are under title Battle.
    - Battle. Screenplay., Revised 1974 January 15.; Typescript with holograph corrections and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Screenplay., 1975 February 12; Written by Donald S. Sanford.; [pencilled revision: 1975 March 12] Typescript multilith with holograph corrections. (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Screenplay., 1975 March 12; Written by Donald S. Sanford.; Typescript multilith. Two copies. (Box 78, Folder 9-10)
    - Revised pages of screenplay organized by date and stage of revision., 1975 April 14; Typescript with holograph corrections and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections and typescript (carbon). (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Murphy's War
    - Correspondence (Box 39)
    - Newsclippings. (Box 39)
    - [screenplay], 1969 June 9; Two copies of first draft with holograph corrections (Box 49)
    - undated., Typescript research notes. (Box 49)
    - [screenplay], 1969 June 2; Revised section, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 49)
    - [screenplay], 1969 June 30; Revised section of typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 49)
    - [screenplay], 1969 July 25; Revised section of typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 49)
    - [screenplay], 1969 July 28; Revised first draft, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 49)
    - [screenplay], 1969 July 28; Revised section of typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 49)
    - [screenplay], 1969 August 21; Two copies of first draft of revised script, typescript (Box 49)
    - First draft [screenplay], 1969 June 4 (Box 49)
    - First draft [screenplay], 1969 June 9; Two copies (Box 49)
  - Never Never Say Die
    - Revised first draft [screenplay], typescript carbon. (Box 42)
    - Revised first draft of screenplay. (Box 42)
    - 1972 January 17., Typescript. (Box 42)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections, revised first draft of screenplay. (Box 42)
  - New Centurions
    - (Box 39)
      Correspondence; Newsclippings.
    - 1971 March 26, Typescript with holograph corrections of stepline. (Box 51)
    - 1971 May 28, Revised first draft of screenplay, carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 51)
    - 1971 April 30, Two copies of first draft screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections (Box 51)
    - 1971 March 26, Typescript of stepline. (Box 51)
    - 1971 May 26, Revised first draft of screenplay, carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 51)
    - 1971 July 19., Carbon of revised draft, screenplay. (Box 52)
    - undated., Carbon of section, (2 copies). (Box 52)
    - 1971 August 6., Revised typescript of screenplay. (Box 52)
    - 1971 June 11, Second revised first draft of screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 52)
    - 1971 June 11, Second revised first draft of screenplay, typescript. (Box 52)
    - 1971 May 28, Revised first draft of screenplay, carbon. (Box 52)
    - 1971 September 23., Typescript of screenplay. (Box 52)
    - undated., Carbon [screenplay] (Box 60)
    - 1971 March 31., Typescript [screenplay] (Box 60)
    - 1971 May 26, Screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 60)
    - 1971 July 19, Screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 60)
    - 1971 September 3, Carbon of screenplay. (Box 60)
    - 1971 September 3, Screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 60)
  - Poseidon Adventure
    - Typescript. (Box 39)
      Workup of story with presentation of characters.
    - Correspondence. (Box 39)
    - 1972 February 10., Revised final schooting script of screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 54)
    - 1971 December 24., First draft screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 54)
    - 1971 December 24., First draft of screenplay, carbon. (Box 54)
    - 1972 February 10., Revised final schooting script of screenplay, typescript. (Box 54)
    - 1972 February 10., Revised final schooting script of screenplay, carbon. (Box 54)
    - 1972 March 14, Third revision of final shooting script of screenplay, typescript, final shooting script (Box 54)
    - 1972 March 24, Third revision of shooting final, typescript of screenplay. (Box 55)
    - 1972 March 24, Typescript of shooting schedule. (Box 55)
    - undated., Typescript of section. (Box 55)
    - undated., Typescript with holograph corrections of section, three copies. (Box 55)
    - undated., Carbon of section. (Box 55)
    - 1972 March 14, Third revision of screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 55)
  - S.S. Poseidon
    - 1971 December 6., First draft screenplay, carbon. (Box 54)
    - 1971 December 3., Revised section, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 54)
    - 1971 December 6., First draft screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 54)
    - 1971 December 6., First draft screenplay, typescript. (Box 54)
  - Score
    - undated., Typescript [screenplay] (Box 57)
  - Shaft
    - (Box 39)
      Distribution audits; Newsclippings.
    - Correspondence., 1972-1973. (Box 39)
    - undated., Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 40)
    - Dialogue corrections., 1970 December 28.; Typescript. (Box 40)
    - Contract agreements (Box 40)
    - Correspondence (Box 40)
    - Document file (Box 40)
    - Press clippings (Box 40)
    - Production notes (Box 40)
    - Roundtree publicity information (Box 40)
    - Shooting schedule. (Box 40)
    - 1972 August 14. (Box 40)
      Soul magazine, with mention of Shaft.
    - 1970 August 19., Six copies [screenplay], typescript. (Box 56)
    - 1970 July 22., Two copies of first draft screenplay, typescript. (Box 56)
    - 1970 July 22., First draft of screenplay, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 56)
    - undated., First draft of screenplay, typescript. (Box 56)
    - undated., Second draft typescript. (Box 57)
    - 1970 November 5, Typescript [screenplay] (Box 57)
    - 1970 November 13, Typescript [screenplay] (Box 57)
    - 1970 November 19, Typescript [screenplay] (Box 57)
    - 1970 August 19., Two copies [screenplay], typescript (Box 57)
    - 1970 December 21, Typescript with holograph corrections [screenplay] (Box 57)
    - 1972 February 9, Four copies of typescript [screenplay] (Box 58)
  - Shaft #2
    - Shaft sequel. (Box 40)
      Correspondence with directors; Outline of story.
    - Shaft sequel., 1972 February 9.; Typescript [screenplay] (Box 57)
    - 1972 January 31., Three copies of fourth draft [screenplay], typescript. (Box 57)
  - Shaft #3
    - Bibliography on Africa and slavery (Box 40)
    - Maps (Box 40)
    - Newsclippings (Box 40)
    - Notes on Shaft in Africa (Box 40)
    - Photographs (Box 40)
    - Research information on Africa. (Box 40)